# **Dhrumil Shah**

## **SUMMARY**

Proficient backend engineer with expertise in Java and JavaScript having 2 years of experience as a design driven Software Engineer, I am looking for positions wherein I am challenged daily to apply these skills and grow as a Software Engineer.

#### **CAREER**

Automatic Data Processing, Parsippany NJ— GPT Summer Intern Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

- Time Labour Management A microservice based web application for employees to effortlessly manage their time, schedule and shifts.
- Learned various kinds of API, and worked on backend. Generated time reports in pdf, excel and csv formats using itext, and apache poi library.
- **Environment:** Spring Boot, Hibernate, Git, BitBucket, Maven, Oracle and Postgres database

## **Axis Bank, Mumbai**— Junior Software Engineer

Sept 2017 - May 2018

Axis Bank is a financial institution, my role and responsibility were as follows:

- Developed a web-based data visualization application which displays bank's financial details. Created RESTful API to fetch data and return JSON.
- Built a highly secure procurement system for handling client's proposals, projects or drafts, worked on super admin and client module.
- Revamped an application to verify the authenticity of customer's signature, using Image processing library in Java (ImageJ).
- Environment: Core Java, JSP, Spring MVC, Hibernate, LDAP, Javascript, Jquery, HTML/CSS, Ajax, SVN, Tomcat, JSON, REST API, Eclipse, Oracle database and OWASP security methodologies.

## **Leo9 Studio, Mumbai**— Junior Software Engineer

Jun 2016 - Aug 2017

Leo9 Studio is a technology plus consultant firm that works with various clients, my accomplishments were as follows:

- Build an in house chatting system for all the working cooperates, which resulted in smooth functioning and coordination of the employees.
- Build JSPs and services for an online bug reporting system that connects clients to developer.
- Created an admin dashboard in a survey system for customers.
- Worked on a chatbot for chatting with customers, using AIML.
- Environment: Core Java, JSP, Hibernate, Node.js, Javascript, Jquery, HTML/CSS, Ajax, Tomcat, Eclipse and MySQL database.

## **PROJECTS**

## **Compact Business Management**

- Build a client management web applications using Node.js and MySql.
- Extensively worked on designing REST API calls and application data flow design.
- Learned how to structure and design a real world Node.js web application.

## **Sentiment Analysis**

- Performed ETL process using Node.js and numpy, scikit-learn python libraries.
- Predicted the polarity of a sentence using various machine learning and natural language techniques with 84% accuracy.

## **Online Examination System**

- Developed a dynamic online examination web application using software engineering techniques. Used JSP, Servlets, MySql, HTML/CSS and JavaScript.
- Learned functioning of client server architecture, database design and software engineering methodology.

+1 (856) 263-1671

dhrumilshah2495@gmail.com

Linked in. GitHub

# TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE AND COMPETENCY

Programming Languages —

Java, Java Frameworks(Spring Boot, MVC and Hibernate), JavaScript(Node.js), HTML/CSS.

**Tools And IDE** — SVN, Git, Apache Tomcat, Cognos, Eclipse, Netbeans, Atom.

**Database** — MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB.

Familiar With — Python (Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn), .net, C/C++, Google Cloud Platform, Heroku, SQLite.

#### **EDUCATION**

New Jersey Institute of
Technology — Masters of Science
in Computer Science
Sep 2018 - Dec 2019

University of Mumbai — Masters of Science in Information Technology

Jun 2016 - Jul 2018

University of Mumbai — Bachelors of Science in Information Technology

Jun 2013 - Apr 2016

## **OTHER PROJECTS**

Huffman(Java), Google
PageRank(Java), Kleinberg
HITS(Java), Apriori(Python),
DNS(Java), UDP Streaming(Java),
Proxy Server(Java), Missing
Cards(Hadoop), Flight Data
Analysis(Hadoop), Chat
Application(Java), Image
Combiner(Node.js)